racinguk.com 2018-08-25

# Racing UK Privacy Policy

**Racing UK Privacy Policy**

The [www.racinguk.com](http://www.racinguk.com/) website and all pages within it (collectively the "Website"), is owned and operated by Racing UK Limited ("us", "our", "we"). We are committed to protecting the privacy of users of this Website. This Privacy Policy explains what information we may collect about you, how we will use it and the steps that we will take to ensure that such information is kept secure.

We are a controller (also known as a data controller) in respect of your personal data, which means we are responsible for determining how we use your personal data. As such, we are registered with the Information Commissioner's Office ("ICO") and our registration number is Z9297632. Although we are a controller, we understand that ultimately it is your personal data and therefore we will only process it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

This Website may have links to other websites. Third party websites should have their own privacy policies and we recommend that you read such policies to find out how your personal details are protected. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these third party websites nor how they will process your personal data.

Please note, we may update this Privacy Policy from time-to-time so you should review it regularly. If we make material changes we will notify you. 

**1\. Personal Data We Collect**

1.1 When you use this Website we may collect details about you which you provide to us in order to access and use our services, such as your name and contact details). 

1.2 We may also collect other information which does not identify you individually but may identify information about you and your device, such as your computer's IP address.

1.3 We may also collect information which you provide to us when you contact us.

1.4 We may also receive information about you from third parties, such as other members of our group and third parties, including Pay-TV operators and betting partners. 

Please note, we do not store the financial details (credit or debit card numbers and billing information) of our subscribers.

We also do not collect any special categories of personal data about you or personal data about you relating to criminal convictions and offences (also known as sensitive personal data). The only exception to this is where you provide this to us unprompted, in which case we will delete such personal data unless there is a specific reason why you have given us this information. 

**2\. Purposes For Processing Your Personal Data**

2.1 In accordance with data protection laws, we will only process your personal data where we have a lawful basis for doing so. In respect of your personal data, these bases are: (i) where it is necessary to provide services to you under the performance of the contract we have with you; (ii) where we are required to do so in accordance with legal or regulatory obligations; (iii) where you have given your consent; and, (iv) where it is in our legitimate interests to process your personal data, provided that none of these prejudice your own rights, freedoms and interests. 

2.2 We process your personal data for the following purposes and in accordance with the following lawful bases:

**Purpose** | **Lawful Basis**  
---|---  
To set-up, administer and manage your account | Necessary for the performance of a contract   
To set-up, administer and manage your account | To provide our services to you  
To receive and respond to your communications and requests | Necessary for the performance of a contract where such communication relates specifically to our services, otherwise consent  
To notify you about updates to our Website and services | Necessary for the performance of a contract  
To ensure that we are able to fulfil our regulatory obligations regarding your account, including by verifying the accuracy of any information you provide us |  Necessary to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation   
To carry out market research campaigns, including contacting you about the services you receive  | Legitimate interests so that we can better understand the products and services that our customers most enjoy  
To prepare statistics relating to the use of our Website and services by you and other customers  |  Legitimate interests so we can understand the use of, and therefore improve, our Website and services  
To provide you with information about changes to our Terms & Conditions and this Privacy Policy  |  Necessary to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation   
To keep you informed of offers and promotions relating to our services and those of other entities within our group, provided that you don't "opt-out" from this option  |  Legitimate interests so we can send you information about our services (and promotions and offers) that you may be interested in   
To support any other purpose necessary for performance of our contractual obligations or specifically stated at the time at which you provided your personal data |  Necessary for the performance of a contract   
To record telephone calls to and from, and live chats with, our customer services representatives for training purposes | Legitimate interests so that we improve our customer services   
To use your name, image, username or location in publicity and marketing, but only where you have provided your express and informed consent for us to do so | Consent  
To share your personal data with other members in our group |  Legitimate interests so we can better understand our customers across the group   
Cookies: Those that are necessary for the operation of the Website, including allowing you to interact with our Website and to recall selections as you move between pages |  Necessary for the performance of the contract   
Cookies: Those that analyse your use of our Website, monitor our web audience and populate certain content on our Website in line with your usage |  Legitimate interest so we can continue to analyse and improve our Website and services   
Cookies: Those that track your journey to and from our Website  |  Legitimate interests so we can understand those that come to and from our website and give effect to any commercial arrangements   
Cookies: Those that identify suspicious activity or false login information  |  Necessary to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation / necessary for the performance of a contact   
Cookies: Those that are used for our and third party marketing |  Consent   
  
**3\. Who Do We Share The Information We Collect With?**

3.1 We may disclose aggregated and anonymised data of which your personal data was originally a constituent part. This information will not contain your personal data and will not be capable of identifying you. 

3.2 We may disclose your personal data to other members in our group. 

3.3 We may appoint certain carefully selected third party processors to process your personal data on our behalf. These third parties will only process your personal data in accordance with our instructions and we will ensure that adequate measures are in place to ensure that your personal data is processed only in accordance with this Privacy Policy and kept secure at all times. 

3.4 We may also share your information with third parties in the following situations, to the extent permitted by law:

• Where we are required to do so by law, court order or governmental authority.

• Where we receive a request from the policy or similar law enforcement agency. 

• If we believe doing so is necessary to protect the rights, property, security, or safety of us, our staff or the public.

• Where required to defend ourselves legally. 

• Where necessary to investigate and defend ourselves against any claims or allegations.

• While negotiating or in relation to a business transaction, such as a merger, change of control, sale of assets, or bankruptcy.

 **4\. Data Security**

We have adopted measures to ensure that users' personal details are not misused, accidentally destroyed, lost or altered. Where information is transferred to a third party, that third party will be required to keep your personal details secure.

 **5\. Transfer of Details Overseas**

Given the global nature of the Internet, use of the Internet to collect and process personal details may involve the transmission of data internationally. Currently we do not process your personal details outside of the UK and Europe. However, if we do so in the future, we will always ensure that any third party to whom your personal details are transferred will take appropriate steps to safeguard your personal details, including standard contractual clauses pursuant to European Decision 2010/87/EC and those that are certified with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework.

 **6\. Updating Your Details**

It is important to ensure that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and up-to-date. Therefore we request that you notify us as soon as any of your personal information which we hold changes. You can update the personal details we hold on you by e-mailing us at: [privacy@racinguk.com](mailto:privacy@racinguk.com).

_ _7.Your Rights __

7.1 You have the following rights in relation to your personal data:

• A right to access your personal data held by us (often known as a subject access request).

• A right to receive certain personal data in machine-readable format.

• A right to have inaccurate personal data rectified.

• A right to object to processing where lawful basis is that it is in our legitimate interests, but please note that we may still process your personal data where there are other relevant lawful bases or where we have compelling grounds to continue processing your personal data in our interests which are not overridden by your rights, interests or freedoms. 

• A right to have certain personal data erased where it is no longer necessary for us to process it, where you have withdrawn your consent pursuant to the paragraph below, where you have objected pursuant to the paragraph above, where your personal data has been unlawfully processed, or where erasing your personal data is required in accordance with a legal obligation.

• A right to withdraw your consent where consent is the lawful basis on which we process your personal data.

• A right to request an explanation of the logic involved where we make decisions about you solely through automated means.

• A right to complain to the ICO. 

• A right to object to any direct marketing.

7.2 If you are unsure about your rights you should contact us or the ICO. You can learn more about your rights here. 

7.3 If you would like to exercise any of your rights then you can do so by contacting us. Please be aware that whilst we will try to accommodate any request you make in respect of your rights they are not absolute rights. This means that we may have to refuse your request or may only be able to comply with it in part. 

7.4 Where you make a request in respect of your rights we will require proof of identification. We may also ask that you clarify your request. If we receive repeated requests or have reason to believe requests are being made unreasonably we may not be required to respond. 

**8\. Retention**

We will retain your personal data for the period necessary for us to provide you with our services and to comply with our legal and regulatory responsibilities. Thereafter we may retain it for a period of time in so far as we deem it still necessary for us to process your personal data. Where it is no longer necessary for us to process your personal data we will delete it. 

**9\. Cookie Policy**

9.1 What is a "Cookie"? "Cookies" are small pieces of information that are issued to your computer when you enter a website. Cookies are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive, and they can be used for a wide range of purposes, such as identifying your computer's previous visits to this Website, and to ascertain the most popular features of this Website. 9.2 Why Do we Use Cookies? Like many other websites, this Website uses cookies as they enable us to identify your computer when you visit this Website. We may also collect information about your computer and internet connection, such as your computer's IP address. This information will not individually identify you and will only be used to recognise your computer's visits to this Website.  
9.3 We also use cookies to develop a clearer picture of which parts of this Website are the most popular to its visitors, and your preferences. You are not obliged to accept cookies and you may amend your browser's settings to prevent it from accepting cookies. 9.4 Further information about why we use cookies is set out in the table in paragraph 5 above. 9.5 You can learn more about cookies and how to disable them here. You can also review third party marketing cookies in your device and disable them here. 

**10\. Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, how we process your personal data or if you wish to make a request in respect of your data protection rights please contact us at [privacy@racinguk.com](mailto:privacy@racinguk.com).

 **11\. General**

Nothing in this Privacy Policy shall restrict or exclude any liability that we have to any party which cannot be excluded by law. This Privacy Policy shall be governed by English law and the courts of England and Wales and shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any disputes arising in relation to this Privacy Policy and this Website.

You can view our full terms and conditions by [clicking here](https://www.racinguk.com/termsandconditions).
